<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>907</id><url>http://nankai.en.school.cucas.cn/en/article/detail?cid=98&amp;pid=58&amp;spid=57&amp;detail=153</url><title>Student Life</title><datetime>unknown date or author</datetime><snippet>tiRecently, the postgraduate recommendation list of Nankai University was confirmed. Top students on the list include 784 female students and 357 male students. It is common to see figures like this. However, it is rare to find that the students living in one dormitory are all selected in the list, and it is even rarer to see all four roommates majoring in double disciplines at the same time. Four students of the class of 2012 in the College of Ideological and Cultural Education succeeded in both being selected into the postgraduate recommendation list and obtaining dual degrees, illustrating another possibility for top students’ achievement.
In this dormitory, Ren Menglei is the best. With the title of the top student in the department, he was recommended to the College of Ideological and Cultural Education of Tsinghua University, majoring in Ideological and Political Education and double majoring in Finance. Niu Siyuan is the book lover. He was recommended to Renmin University of China, majoring in Scientific Socialism and double majoring in Business Management. Shu Gaolei is the most hardworking student. He was recommended to the College of Ideological and Cultural Education of Nankai University, while furthering his study in Ideological and Political Education and double majoring in Business Management. He is also very involved in various social activities and practices. Yang Qi is the most reliable. He was recommended to the College of Ideological and Cultural Education of Nankai University as well, while furthering his study in Ideological and Political Education and double majoring in Finance. Meanwhile he is also the class monitor as well as leader of several student organizations. Before he starts his postgraduate study, he will work in the University for two years.
“Each one of us has our own characteristics and purposes,” the four roommates said. Although they are considered as top students, they do not go to classes, study and have meals together. Instead, they play basketball and hold bedtime conversations together.
Among the four, Ren Menglei and Niu Siyuan are more academic. They hold a regular routine, staying in the library and classrooms every day. Ren is considered a quality person, which is proven by his outstanding study ability, nice disposition and popularity. His class notes were so detailed that became a model for note-taking for his classmates.
Niu Siyuan is a book lover and thinks the deepest. “If he is free, he reads,” say his roommates. His reading covers history, politics, celebrity biographies, etc. Steven Jobs is the one he admires the most. “He changed the world by his ideas and through his effort. Everyone should have his own ideas and put them into practice so that he can become valuable to society. These days, I am reading The Tragedy of a Great Nation...” Though Niu is a quiet person, he cannot stop talking when it comes to academic study. “He is thoughtful and creative. He is the one the most well-suited for academic study.” Ren Menglei holds a high opinion of Niu Siyuan. 
Shu Gaolei and Yang Qi are more active. They leave the dorm early in the morning and come back late. “They seldom take naps and sometimes they study in the classroom overnight.” Shu Gaolei, a handsome boy who is 187cm tall, is praised as a talent in everything. He does not only take part in various art and sports activities, but also is a fan of calligraphy. He even can play instruments from time to time. His roommates “revealed” that he wrote novels, but he never shared them with others. Recently, he also has the experience of being a director. He studied hard in photography and video editing software and organized a team to make the film, Fang Shiyu’s Discovery of Nankai, which is now being played in Tianjin International Channel.　　
Yang Qi is now a teacher. He has joined the advisor team and he determines to combine  theories with practice. “He can be excited when he talks about students. We all support him to pass on his reliability to his students,” his roommates said. “Reliability is in fact a sense of responsibility. Nankai students should cultivate their consciousness of responsibility, “said Yang Qi.
　“Each of us has some advantages worth being learned by each other,” Shu said. Ren takes a lot of duties in the dormitory and often helps others. Niu is always the “host” of the bedtime conversation. Yang’s passion and determination in education is admired by everyone, though, he is still confused by his future direction.
“The most obvious characteristic of our dorm is that we are similar but not same. We are all active and ambitious,” Yang Qi said. “In this year’s opening ceremony, I am impressed by a word said by President Gong Ke. He said that Nankai students only have one direction, which is always going upward. I use this saying to encourage my students as well.”</snippet></doc>